# Yekyung Kim

sigma89kim@gmail.com +82 10-3128-7393

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

## Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning

My research goal is to build an **efficient** and **trustworthy** system that connects humans and machines leveraging language as a bridge. From learning machine knowledge with limited resources to expanding machine knowledge to have human-like abilities, I am interested in the reliable communication between humans and machines and how they can learn and teach knowledge efficiently.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Hyundai Motors Group

Feb 2021 - Present

Senior Research Engineer

Seoul, Korea

- Developed natural language understanding (NLU) and out-of-distribution (OOD) detection systems for in-car voice assistants and customer service chatbot.
- Applied data-centric approaches such as text generation and data re-weighting for improving robustness of systems
- Collaborated in research projects to tackle various real-world problems, e.g., low-resource, robustness, using data augmentation [1], active learning [2], and OOD detection based on data informativeness [3]

LG Electronics

Dec 2014 - Feb 2021

Research Engineer

Seoul, Korea

- Developed multi-action intent classifier and named entity recognition (NER) [5] in Korean, English based on deep learning for Incheon Airport Robot, customer service and home appliances control chatbot.
- Designed and developed algorithm to measure uncertainty for active learning to minimize the labeling cost in classification and sequence tagging tasks [4]
- Developed algorithm for detecting anomaly battery draining on devices and recommendation system for tip contents based on user segmentation using machine learning approach (equipped on LG Mobile)

### Carnegie Mellon University

Apr 2019 - Aug 2019

Visiting Scientist

Pittsburgh, United States

- Advisor: Prof. Jaime Carbonell (Language Technology Institute)
- Researched hybrid method combining active learning and self-training to efficiently exploit information from unlabeled data to minimize the labeling cost

# **EDUCATION**

#### Seoul National University

Mar 2013 - Feb 2015

M.S. in Convergence Science and Technology

- Advisor: Prof. Kyogu Lee (Music and Audio Research Group)
- Thesis: "Crowds vs. Broadcasters: Predicting Billboard Rank Using Characteristic of Music Listening Behavior in Twitter" (*Outstanding Paper Award*)

#### Chung-Ang University

Mar 2008 - Feb 2013

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

### University of California, Berkeley

May 2011 - Aug 2011

Visiting Student, Summer Session

## **PUBLICATIONS**

[1] Yekyung Kim, Seohyeong Jeong, Kyunghyun Cho. "LINDA: Learning to Interpolate in Natural Language Processing" *Under Review at Journal of Transactions on Machine Learning Research (TMLR)*, 2022

- [2] Jaehyung Kim, **Yekyung Kim**, Dongyeop Kang. "infoVerse: Dataset Characterization with Multi-dimensional Meta-information" arXiv, 2022
- [3] Ryan Koo, **Yekyung Kim**, Dongyeop Kang, Jaehyung Kim. "Meta-Crafting: Combining Different Meta-informations for Detecting Out-of-distribution" *Under Review at European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)*, 2022
- [4] Yekyung Kim. "Deep Active Learning for Sequence Labeling based on Diversity and Uncertainty in Gradient" Workshop on Life-long Learning for Spoken Language Systems at AACL, 2021
- [5] Yejin Kim, **Yekyung Kim**\*. "Learning Sub-Character level representation for Korean Named Entity Recognition" *FLAIR*, 2021 (\*equal contributions)
- [6] Yekyung Kim, Bongwon Suh, and Kyogu Lee. "#Nowplaying the Future Billboard: Mining Music Listening Behaviors of Twitter Users for Hit Song Prediction" Workshop on Social Media Retrieval and Analysis, SoMeRA at SIGIR, 2014
- [7] Ramik Sadana, **Yekyung Kim**, Bongwon Suh, Eunyee Koh. "A Visual Analytics Approach to Summarizing Tweets" *Industrial Session at SIGIR*, 2014

#### IN PREPARATION

Yekyung Kim, Seohyeong Jeong, Kyunghyun Cho. "Conformal Prediction for Autoregressive Sequence Generation"

Yekyung Kim. "Few-shot Fine-tuning with chain-of-thought"

Yekyung Kim, Juae Kim, Dongyeop Kang. "Saliency based Text Augmentation"

# HONORS AND AWARDS

AI Specialist (Selected one of the top 12 researchers), LG Electronics	2019
Outstanding Paper Award, Seoul National University	2015
The Grand Prize in Datathon, Ministry of Science and ICT	2014
Merit-based scholarship, Seoul National University	2014
BK21 Research Fellowship, Brain Korea 21	2014
The OSS Award, North East Asia Open Source Software	2013
The Gold Prize in Open Source Software World Challenge, NIPA	2012
Software Maestro Scholarship, NIPA	2012
Engineering Scholarship, Chung-Ang University	2012
Academic Excellence Scholarship, Chung-Ang University	2011, 2012

# PATENTS

**Yekyung Kim**, Gyeonghoon Kim, Yejin Kim. Voice processing device and voice processing method. KR Patent 10-2306-3930000

Heungnam Kim, Inae Ha, **Yekyung Kim**. MOBILE TERMINAL AND CONTROL METHOD FOR THE MOBILE TERMINAL. KR Patent 10-2364-0870000

#### INTERNSHIP

# Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute Research Intern

Jan 2013 - Mar 2013 Daejeon, Korea

- Collaborator: Ph.D Jeongdan Choe
- Collaborated in research projects of unmanned vehicle parking system

#### Seoul National University

Jan 2012 - Feb 2012

Research Intern

Suwon, Korea

- Collaborator: Prof. Kyogu Lee
- Collaborated in developing movie genre prediction model based on scenario text with topic modeling algorithm

### Chung-ang University

Oct 2010 - Nov 2012

Research Intern

Seoul, Korea

- Collaborator: Prof. Byungwoo Hong
- Collaborated in research projects of computer vision and medical imaging processing system

EXTRA- CIRRICULAR ACTIVITIES		ware Maestro, The Ministry of Knowledge Economy stem of Women in Science, Engineering and Technology	2012 2012 2011 2011
ACADEMIC SERVICE	-	ds in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP): 2022 on Processing Systems (NeurIPS): 2022	
INVITED TALKS	LINDA: Learning to Interpolate in Natural Language Processing Cohere.ai (online), Feb 2022		
	Saliency based Text Augmentation Minnesota NLP Group (online), Sep 2021		
TECHNICAL STRENGTHS	Computer Languages Software Tools	python, java, C/C++ PyTorch, Tensorflow, MATLAB, R	